

FRONT-END

ES Latest
ReactJS
VueJs
Ionic
Redux or Relay
D3JS
Vanilla JS
HTML5
SASS/LESS/CSS3

BACK-END

NodeJS TypeScript Python

Express Flask Django

DATABASE

DynamoDB Mongo GraphQL

DESIGN PATTERNS

DEV OPS

Docker Heroku

TESTING

Jest Jasmine PyTest

METHODOLOGIES

Lean Architecture Functional Code Clean/SOLID Code Agile/Scrum Pair Programming

AWS

CloudFormation Lambda Dynamo DB API Gateway SNS/SQS S3

INTERESTS

Open Souce Development Big Data Graph Databases AI, ML, & DL

JILLIAN MAGSAYSAY

SENIOR LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Denver/Boulder CO

www.jillianmagsaysay.com

jcmagsay

(708) 973-0502

 ★ beerBizzo

MISSION STATEMENT

As a **software architect**, every byte of code that I touch, results in a beautiful, comprehensive, library or framework. With my expansive full-stack experience, every design and architectural concept is taken into consideration to create a simple work-flow supported by intentionality. Modern, modular, atomic, and functional are my favorite techniques when it comes to creating software. With my diverse skillset and background through multiple industries, I can bring software to life through creative and thoughtful

EXPERIENCE

Launch Forth Crowd-Source Industrial Engineering Platform

10/2017 - Present

Senior Lead Software Engineer

- Managing platform team composed of Front-End/Back-End Engineers, UX/UI Designers, and QA
- Requirement gathering for UX, Design, and Engineering teams for high-level architectures
- Collaborating with other Senior Engineers on workflows and platform architecture
- Defining and overseeing SDLC ensuring high-quality deliverables matching product roadmap
- Leading requirement gathering, design iteration, development implementations, testing, and CI/CD
- Working closely with stakeholders and product team to provide Platform Team status updates, deliver scheduled iterative releases, and make design decisions throughout the SDLC
- Participation in Code and Design Review ensuring Engineering team can achieve MVP features while meeting baseline standards and best practices.
- Code ownership at a capacity of 60% during a two week long agile sprint
- Responsible for Agile Planning and Ceremonies (Standup, Grooming/Planning, Story Authoring, Retrospectives)
- Improving failing processes -- Platform team achievment of burndown productivity from 10% to 90% completion
- Regularly practicing 3 Pillars of Technical Leadership (Ownership, Execution, and Encouragement)

Mondo Robot Digital Agency

07/2016 - 10/2017

Senior Software Engineer, Projects Lead

- Built web and mobile apps in various industries including but not limited to: Telecom/Virtual Communication, Operations Management, Healthcare Research, Science & Space Archaeology, Beer, and Cycling
- Created new project boilerplates to expedite and position projects two weeks ahead of schedule
- Efficiently working with 3rd-Parties serving up APIs, CMSs, Content Copy Documents, and other resources to saturate web and mobile applications
- Created documentation for new employee onboarding, new projects, and engineering team guidelines
- Founded and led Front-End working group to emphasize and push best practices, modern standards, and cutting edge technologies on the Engineering team
- Mentored Junior and Mid-Level Engineers in technical communication through weekly 15 minute dev chats
- Participated in several brainstorming and concept creation activities -- one of which became a profitable and billable project for a pillar client
- Consistently posting articles and blog posts in Engineering and Design team Slack channels for knowledge sharing purposes

10-4 Systems Transportation and Operations Management

11/2014 - 07/2016

Lead Front-End & Senior Full Stack Engineer

- Extensive work with Google APIs to create a real-time operational views for transportation companies/orgs
- Generated custom analytical and charting solutions using D3 APIs
- Created several wrapper frameworks for JQWidgets, D3.js, Google Maps API, and MDL frameworks
- Assisted training teams and writing extensive documentation on Git & Git Flow after SVN migration
- Created custom 10-4 UI component library following Material Design Guidelines
- Wrote proposals, documents, and technical specification documents for new tooling and frameworks
- Extensive pair programming with Jr. Developers to teach new concepts, fundamentals, and methodologies

EDUCATION

Indiana University B.S. Informatics, Focus Computer Science & Entrepreneurship Colorado State University B.S. Information Technology

References available upon request